

VIKRAM A TANWAR

Cell: +971-56-4893702-/ 50-6819665 - hotelier.vikram@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Industrious and motivated hotel manager with 20 years of experience in the hospitality industry. Effective at managing all types of people and maintaining a positive and productive atmosphere. Focused on elevating the hotel guest experience and representing the brand effectively.

SKILLS

- Budgeting and forecasting
- Results-oriented
- Superb time management skills
- Work flow planning
- Management information systems
- Unsurpassed work ethic
- Natural leader
- Cost reduction strategies

- Process improvement
- Performance evaluations
- Purchasing and procurement
- Contract negotiation
- Detail-oriented
- Organized
- Revenue Management

WORK HISTORY

02/2019- 08/2021 **Hotel Manager**

Al Khoory Hotel Apartments and Al Khoory Inn (2019 -2020) - Al Khoory Hotels -Dubai, UAE

- Manage 144 Hotel Apartments with AED 10 million in Annual Revenue.
- Coordinate and implement sales and marketing activities of the property.
- Review and analyze monthly revenue numbers, stats, and guest comments to take appropriate action for further improvements and enhancements towards revenue and service excellence.
- Communicated with existing and perspective clients to establish a strong professional relationship.
- Demonstrated ability to recruit, hire, and train a highly motivated team.

- Conducted coaching/counselling sessions, performance evaluations, discipline documents, and terminations.
- Responsible for the preparation of property budgets and ensure purchases are within the budget.
- P & L management achieved profitability through revenue growth and cost control. Exceeded company year over year goals resulting in bonus pay-outs.
- Successfully resolved aging accounts receivable issues resulting in no bad debt write offs.

Key achievements:

- Slashed the number of customer complaints by 30% through ensuring that staff followed guest Standard Operating procedures and guidelines.
- Received high level of accreditation on TripAdvisor and received the Certificate of Excellence Award 2019/2021.
- Core Team member in SOP formation for the Al Khoory Group of Hotels.
- Consistently achieve and surpass the Budgeted occupancies and Revenue targets in 2019 and 2020.

12/2015 to 01/2019 **Operations Manager**

Golden Tulip Nihal Palace Hotel – Dubai, UAE

- Manage all activities of the property including employees, maintenance, sales, and profit/loss controls.
- Maximize revenues by increasing the average daily rate (ADR) through Internet based third-party wholesalers.
- Evaluated and re-negotiated all vendor services contracts, resulting in a 15% annual savings while maintaining quality.
- Established significant training programs for each department resulting in increased guest satisfaction.
- Perform goal setting, motivation/ discipline of employees, labor expense control, control of general expenses and resolving guest related issues in accordance with the company goals.
- Coordinate, direct and manage the hotel operation to achieve maximum profitability, ensure guest satisfaction, protect the financial aspects of the business and maintain the building.
- Direct and manage property operations to assure optimum performance and continual improvement in the five Key Result Areas (guest service, employees, sales/marketing, property appearance, and profit/financial control).
- Ensure that product quality standards are met in all areas of the hotel as it relates to the appearance, levels of maintenance and cleanliness; establish and maintain preventative maintenance programs to protect the physical assets of the hotel.
- Oversee the guest service function to ensure corrective action is taken to resolve guest complaints and ensure superior guest service is delivered.

07/2014 to 11/2015 General Manager

Ramee Hotels & Resorts – Dubai, UAE

- Earned exceptional ratings and testimonials from clients on Booking.com.
- Maximizing GOP by cost effective measures and ensuring that quality standards are maintained to achieve high guest satisfaction.
- Implementing customer feedback system to enhance customer satisfaction levels.
- Sourcing local vendors for supplies, finalizing rate contracts with quality specifications.
- Monitoring the sales team on daily basis and assessing materialization.
- Handling Credit Control on outstanding and conducting reviews on a weekly basis.
- Preparing training schedule of all departments in coordination with HR team.
- Overseeing the preparation of MIS reports on a monthly basis; reviewing and analyzing the reports.
- Responsible for budgeting of revenue & expense (operating & capital) on a yearly basis.
- Conducting daily meetings with department heads to streamline the channel of communication
- Ensuring HACCP Standards are in total adherence

07/2011 to 06/2014 General Manager

The Beatle Hotel – Mumbai, India.

- Received Three Awards for Guest Satisfaction and Being The Best Mid-Segment Business Hotel in Mumbai.
- Elevated the Trip advisor ratings and also received "Certificate of Excellence 2014"
- Enhanced the GOP to 45% by adopting various corrective measures.
- Reduced the HLP costs by 35% by implementing various energy saving measures.
- Stabilized food and beverage cost by increasing the foot falls by activating innovative marketing strategies
- Assisted with the creation of the marketing strategy and advertising initiatives that were used to promote the facility to the public.
- Ensured that each guest's experience was positive, memorable and consistent.

03/2009 to 06/2011 Executive Assistant Manager

Yogi Group of Hotels – Navi Mumbai, MH

- Supervises the overall activities of Front Office, Housekeeping, Laundry and Security department.
- Monitors the personnel of these operations to ensure guests receive prompt, cordial attention and personal recognition.
- Ensures staff, particularly guest contact personnel, known repeat guests and other VIPs and provide special attention and recognition.
- Coordinates exchange of pertinent information between departments within the Rooms Division and directs exchange of information with other departments.

- Consults with Department Heads and General Manager on an ongoing basis to improve business conduct.
- Assumes overall responsibility for maintaining presentation standards to ensure facilities and equipment are clean, in good repair and well maintained.
- Schedules and regularly conducts routine inspections of areas under control.
- Maintains appropriate standards of conduct, dress, hygiene, uniforms, appearance and posture of Room Division employees.
- Conducts comprehensive monthly departmental meetings to include review of procedures and events which warrant special handling and detailed information.
- Promotes Inter-hotel sales and in-house facilities.
- Monitors and controls the inventories for operating equipment and supplies.
- Communicates to the General Manager to his/her delegate, and other Department heads, all information likely to be of interest to them.
- Monitors and controls the Room Division Operation in the areas of revenue expenditure, profitable and performance against budget.

07/2007 to 02/2009 Front Office Manager

Fortune Park Hotels Ltd. – Navi Mumbai, MH

- Pre-Opening member widely exposed to the various activities of opening a hotel.
- Ensure that guest data and management reporting is processed efficiently and accurately while maintaining proper security standards.
- Ensure that all accounting transaction and cash handling procedures are in compliance.
- Conduct regular monthly meetings with members of the Front Office and Communication Team to address current initiatives, projects and long term goals.
- Pro-actively identify potential guest issues.
- Recruit, hire, train and retain associates for all supervised departments.
- Develop monthly training items to foster development and cross training with other departments.
- Perform associate evaluations, provide coaching and development.
- Monitor guest satisfaction processes, and respond to guest concerns, and inquiries.

10/2005 to 07/2007 Assistant Front Office Manager

Grand Hyatt Mumbai – Mumbai, MH

- Managed work flow to exceed quality service goals.
- Identified individual development needs with appropriate training.
- Trained staff on operating procedures and company services.
- Assumed ownership over team productivity and managed work flow to meet or exceed quality service goals.
- Promptly responded to inquiries and requests from prospective customers.
- Adhered to all confidentiality requirements at all times.
- Investigated and resolved guest inquiries and complaints in an empathetic manner.

09/2002 to 09/2005 Senior Guest Service Executive

Burj Al Arab Jumeirah – Dubai, UAE

- Nominated twice for the best Employee of the Month in year 2004.
- Certified Task trainer of the department.
- In-charge of the floor operations, supervising butlers and housekeeping staff to ensure smooth check in/checkouts and familiarizing the guest with hotel facilities.
- Increasing revenue by up-selling suites and cross-selling restaurants within Jumeirah International.
- Maintaining and updating guest folios, keeping dockets up to date, daily credit checks and preparing invoices for travel agents and companies.
- Induction of new recruits in the team by providing floor training and Fidelio training.
- Assisting managers in daily operations and performing specific duties assigned by managers.

The Oberoi, Mumbai – Mumbai, MH

EDUCATION

2016	Certified Hotel Administrator American Hotel & Lodging Educational Institute - Orlando, USA
2008	MBA: Hospitality National Institute of Management - Mumbai, MH
1997	Bachelor of Arts: Economics Jai Hind College - Mumbai, MH